window.__examLoadCallback({
  "title": "Computer_Network - Computer_Network — Slot 20 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Computer_Network — Slot 20",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>The distance between two stations M and N is L kilometers. All frames are K bits long. The propagation delay per kilometer is t seconds. Let R bits/second be the channel capacity. Assuming that processing delay is negligible, the minimum number of bits for the sequence number field in a frame for maximum utilization, when the sliding window protocol is used, is: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\([log_{2}\\frac{2LtR+2K}{K}]\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\([log_{2}\\frac{2LtR}{K}]\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\([log_{2}\\frac{2LtR+K}{K}]\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\([log_{2}\\frac{2LtR+2K}{2K}]\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>\\([log_{2}\\frac{2LtR+K}{K}]\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1267/gate2007-69#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>The message 11001001 is to be transmitted using the CRC polynomial \\(x^{3}\\)+1 to\nprotect it from errors. The message that should be transmitted is: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>11001001000</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>11001001011</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>11001010</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>110010010011</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>11001001011</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1266/gate2007-68#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>The address of a class B host is to be split into subnets with a 6-bit subnet number. What is the maximum number of subnets and the maximum number of hosts in each subnet? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>62 subnets and 262142 hosts</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>64 subnets and 262142 hosts</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>62 subnets and 1022 hosts.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>64 subnets and 1024 hosts.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>62 subnets and 1022 hosts.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1265/gate2007-67#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>In a token ring network the transmission speed is \\(10^{7}\\) bps and the propagation\nspeed is 200 metres/\\(\\mu s\\). The 1-bit delay in this network is equivalent to: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>500 metres of cable.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>200 metres of cable.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>50 metres of cable.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>20 metres of cable.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>20 metres of cable.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1264/gate2007-66#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>There are n stations in a slotted LAN. Each station attempts to transmit with a probability p in each time slot. What is the probability that ONLY one station transmits in a given time slot? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(np(1-p)^{n-1}\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\((1-p)^{n-1}\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(p(1-p)^{n-1}\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(1-(1-p)^{n-1}\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(np(1-p)^{n-1}\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1263/gate2007-65#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>Which one of the following uses UDP as the transport protocol? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>HTTP</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Telnet</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>DNS</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>SMTP</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>DNS</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1218/gate2007-20#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>In Ethernet when Manchester encoding is used, the bit rate is: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Half the baud rate.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Twice the baud rate</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Same as the baud rate</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>Half the baud rate.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1217/gate2007-19#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>A subnetted Class B network has the following broadcast address: 144.16.95.255 <br>\nIts subnet mask <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2006)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>is necessarily 255.255.224.0</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>is necessarily 255.255.240.0</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>is necessarily 255.255.248.0</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>could be any one of 255.255.224.0, 255.255.240.0,255.255.248.0</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>could be any one of 255.255.224.0, 255.255.240.0,255.255.248.0</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3614/gate2006-it-70\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>A program on machine X attempts to open a UDP connection to port 5376 on a machine Y, and a TCP connection to port 8632 on machine Z. However, there are no applications listening at the corresponding ports on Y and Z. An ICMP Port Unreachable error will be generated by <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2006)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Y but not Z</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Z but not Y</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Neither Y nor Z</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Both Y and Z</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>Both Y and Z</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3613/gate2006-it-69\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>On a wireless link, the probability of packet error is 0.2. A stop-and-wait protocol is used to transfer data across the link. The channel condition is assumed to be independent of transmission to transmission. What is the average number of transmission attempts required to transfer 100 packets? <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2006)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>100</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>125</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>150</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>200</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>125</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3612/gate2006-it-68\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>A link of capacity 100 Mbps is carrying traffic from a number of sources. Each source generates an on-off traffic stream; when the source is on, the rate of traffic is 10 Mbps, and when the source is off, the rate of traffic is zero. The duty cycle, which is the ratio of on-time to off-time, is 1:2. When there is no buffer at the link, the minimum number of sources that can be multiplexed on the link so that link capacity is not wasted and no data loss occurs is S1. Assuming that all sources are synchronized and that the link is provided with a large buffer, the maximum number of sources that can be multiplexed so that no data loss occurs is S2. The values of S1 and S2 are, respectively, <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2006)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>10 and 30</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>12 and 25</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>5 and 33</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>15 and 22</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>10 and 30</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3611/gate2006-it-67\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>A router has two full-duplex Ethernet interfaces each operating at 100 Mb/s. Ethernet frames are at least 84 bytes long (including the Preamble and the Inter-Packet-Gap). The maximum packet processing time at the router for wirespeed forwarding to be possible is (in micro-seconds) <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2006)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>0.01</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>3.36</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>6.72</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>8</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>3.36</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3610/gate2006-it-66\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>Suppose that it takes 1 unit of time to transmit a packet (of fixed size) on a communication link. The link layer uses a window flow control protocol with a window size of N packets. Each packet causes an ack or a nak to be generated by the receiver, and ack/nak transmission times are negligible. Further, the round trip time on the link is equal to N units. Consider time i &gt; N. If only acks have been received till time i(no naks), then the goodput evaluated at the transmitter at time i(in packets per unit time) is <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2006)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(1- \\dfrac{ N}{i}\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(\\dfrac{i}{(N + i)}\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>1</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(1 - e^{\\left(\\frac{i}{N}\\right)}\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(1- \\dfrac{ N}{i}\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3608/gate2006-it-64\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>A router uses the following routing table:<br>\n\\(\\begin{array}{|l|l|l|} \\hline \\textbf {Destination} &amp; \\textbf { Mask} &amp; \\textbf{Interface} \\\\\\hline \\text {144.16.0.0} &amp; \\text{255.255.0.0} &amp; \\text{eth$0$} \\\\\\hline\\text {144.16.64.0} &amp; \\text{255.255.224.0} &amp; \\text{eth$1$} \\\\\\hline\\text {144.16.68.0} &amp; \\text{255.255.255.0} &amp; \\text{eth$2$}\\\\\\hline \\text {144.16.68.64} &amp; \\text{255.255.255.224} &amp; \\text{eth$3$}\\\\\\hline\\end{array}\\)<br>\nPacket bearing a destination address 144.16.68.117 arrives at the router. On which interface will it be forwarded? <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2006)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>eth0</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>eth1</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>eth2</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>eth3</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>eth2</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3607/gate2006-it-63-isro2015-57\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following statement(s) is TRUE?<br><br>\nI.  A hash function takes a message of arbitrary length and generates a fixed length code.<br>\nII. A hash function takes a message of fixed length and generates a code of variable length.<br>\nIII. A hash function may give the same hash value for distinct messages. <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2006)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>I only</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>II and III only</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>I and III only</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>II only</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>I and III only</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3559/gate2006-it-20\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
});
